# Marina Sideri

Full Stack JavaScript Developer

marina.sideri@outlook.com | a 075 3462 4167 Website marisid.github.io/portfolio-website

LinkedIn @ linkedin.com/in/marinasideri | GitHub @ github.com/marisid

# **Summary**

I am a full-stack JavaScript developer, currently studying at Founders & Coders, a highly selective 4-month coding course in London. With a background in civil engineering and over 3 years of experience in technical consultancy roles, I decided to transfer my engineering thinking and problem solving skills in the creative world of web development. I am currently seeking for a permanent role with opportunities for growth and learning. I am a hard-working, enthusiastic individual with excellent team working skills and experience in pair-programming, test driven development, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Node.js and SQL databases. A sample of my work on individual and group projects can be found in my portfolio website.

# **Skills & Training**

| Front-end  | Back-end                                | Other                   |
|--|---|-------------------------|
| JavaScript   | JavaScript (ES5 & ES6)                  | Git flow and GitHub     |
| Semantic HTML5                                       | Node.js                                 | Markdown                |
| CSS3 and BEM methodology                             | npm                                     | RESTful APIs            |
| SASS   | hapi.js                                 | Pair-programming        |
| Testing using Q-Unit and Jasmine                     | Handlebars.js templating                | Test driven development |
| User Experience and User Interface responsive design | Testing using Tape                      | Deployment on Heroku    |
|  | SQL databases<br>(PostgreSQL and MySQL) | Code reviewing          |
|  | OAuth and session management            | Agile methodologies     |

### Founders & Coders coding course

Oct 2016 - Feb 2017

- Intensive 4-month coding course in full stack JavaScript web development
- Peer-led learning environment with emphasis on pair-programming, test driven development and agile methodologies
- Final projects include building prototypes and MVPs for charities and social enterprises

## CS50 Introduction to Computer Science | edX - Harvard University

Jul 2016 – Mar 2017 (expected)

- Topics studied include algorithms, problem solving, data structures and web development.
- Languages studied include C, PHP, SQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS.

# **Experience**

# Geotechnical Engineer at Arup, London

Aug 2015 - Feb 2016

- Report writing, preparation of geotechnical desk studies including risk assessments for site developments in London
- Team working in multidisciplinary projects, collaborated with engineers of different backgrounds to develop foundation design solutions
- Prepared and delivered team presentations regarding the progress of ongoing projects and research

# Geotechnical Engineer at Geotechnical Consulting Group (GCG), London Sept 2012 – Jul 2015

- Technical expertise in numerical analysis for a variety of geotechnical engineering projects and preparation of technical reports
- Project management duties including client contact, preparation for meetings, presentations to the clients, pricing, quoting and invoicing
- Administration duties including organising internal workload meetings, creating and distributing meeting minutes, archiving and filing documents

### Education

### **Imperial College London**

Sept 2011 - Sept 2012

MSc in Soil Mechanics and Business Management

Grade: Distinction (awarded two prizes and a scholarship)

#### National Technical University of Athens (NTUA), Greece

Sept 2005 - Sept 2010

Diploma in Civil Engineering (equivalent to MEng)

Major in Geotechnical Engineering – Grade: 85.2/100 (equivalent to 2:1)

### **Interests & Hobbies**

Travelling, playing board and live escape games, mindfulness and meditation, teaching code, volunteering as a qualified Team London Ambassador.

References available on request